Guide to the Sydney Howard Gay Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Sydney Howard Gay Papers,
1748-1931
Gay, Sydney Howard, 1814-1888.
81 boxes
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078801
History
Journalist, author. Gay, the son of Ebenezer and Mary Alleyne Otis Gay, was an active abolitionist before and during the Civil War. He edited the ANTI-SLAVERY STANDARD and during the Civil War was managing editor of the NEW YORK TRIBUNE. In 1867 he became managing editor of the CHICAGO TRIBUNE and served on the editorial board of the SATURDAY EVENING POST. He was the author of several books. In 1845 he married Elizabeth Neall of Philadelphia, who was also active in abolitionist work and the woman's rights movement.
Scope and Content
Letters written to Gay from political and literary contemporaries such as Horace Greeley, Charles Sumner, and William Bryant; reports in letter form from his reporters at the front during the Civil War; and personal correspondence including many letters from his wife. Letters written to Mrs. Gay from family friends and business associates including many from her husband. Correspondence of other members of the Gay family including Walter Gay, Sarah Gay, and Allan Gay. Diaries, notebooks, and journals of Sydney Howard Gay.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged by category. Boxes 1-71: Cataloged correspondence; Boxes 72-76: Manuscripts & documents; Box 77: Genealogical materials & photographs; Boxes 78-79: Printed materials.
Subjects
Chicago Tribune (Firm); Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878.; Chapman, Maria Weston, 1806-1885.; Child, Lydia Maria, 1802-1880.; Gay, Elizabeth Neall.; Gay, Jotham.; Gay, Sarah.; Gay, Walter.; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872.; Higgins, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911.; Hill, Asams Sherman, 1833-1910.; Lowell, Josephine Shaw, 1843-1905.; Mott, Lucretia, 1793-1880.; Phillips, Wendell, 1811-1884.; Powell, Aaron M. (Aaron Macy), 1832-1899.; Pugh, Sarah.; Quincy, Edmund, 1808-1877.; Richardson, Albert D. (Albert Deane), 1833-1869.; Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives.; United States--Politics and government--19th century.; African Americans--History.; Antislavery movements.; Women--Suffrage.; Journalism.; Accounts.; Agreements.; Albums.; Bills.; Bills of exchange.; Contracts.; Deeds.; Diaries.; Dispatches.; Drafts.; Drawings.; Essays.; Fiction.; Financial records.; Genealogies.; Insurance policies.; Inventories.; Invitations.; Journals.; Leases.; Lectures.; Lists.; Minutes.; Mortgages.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Petitions.; Photographs.; Poems.; Promissory notes.; Receipts.; Releases.; Reports.; Resolutions.; Reviews.; Sermons.; Speeches.; Translations.; Wills.; Abolitionists.; Authors, American.; Editors.; Journalists.; Quaker abolitionists.; Soldiers.; Suffragists.; Women abolitionists.; National Anti-Slavery Standard.; Saturday evening post.; New York tribune.
Access Restrictions
Available for faculty, students, and researchers engaged in scholarlyor publication projects.
Acquisition
1953 M-53 Bancroft Purchase
Alternate Formats
Microfilm available.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Abbot, Joseph Hale (Box 1)
  - Adam, Phebe G. (Box 1)
  - Adams, Alice (Box 1)
  - Adams, Charles F. (Box 1)
  - Adams, John Quincy (1767-1848) (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey 1836-1907 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, William, 1819-1882 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Frederic (Box 1)
  - Allen, Margaret A. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Philip (Box 1)
  - Amberley, Katherine Louisa Stanley, Viscountess (Box 1)
  - Ames, Julius R. (Box 1)
  - Amory, Thomas C. (Box 1)
  - Anderson, George C. (Box 1)
  - Andrew, John T. (Box 1)
  - Andrews, C. A. (Box 1)
  - Andrew, John Albion, 1818-1867 (Box 1)
  - Andrew, John Forrester, 1850-1895 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Edmund (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Emily R. (Box 1)
  - Andrews Son & MacLaine (Box 1)
  - Anthony, Susan Brownell, 1820-1906 (Box 1)
  - Aphul, W. N. (Box 1)
  - Appleton, D.F. (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Kos (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Isaac Newston, 1815-1884 (Box 1)
  - Arrington, W. B. (Box 1)
  - Ashurst, Elizabeth See Bardouneau-Narcy (Box 1)
  - Astor, William Backhouse (Box 1)
  - Atcheson, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, William Parsons, 1820-1890 (Box 1)
  - Attwood, Gilbert (Box 1)
  - Avery, Elroy McKendree, 1844-1835 (Box 1)
  - Ayer, James Cook, 1818-1878 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey 1830-1907 (Box 2)
  - Bacon, Mary D. (Box 2)
  - Bagley, I. L. (Box 2)
  - Bailey, J.F. (Box 2)
  - Baker, William (Box 2)
  - Baker, William F. (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Balhahah, Mrs Alex (Box 2)
  - Bancroft, M.S. (Box 2)
  - Bangs, E.K. (Box 2)
  - Banker, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Banks, Clara (Box 2)
  - Bardouneau-Narcy, Eliza[beth] A. Ashurst (Box 2)
  - Barker, Joseph, 1806-1875 (Box 2)
  - Barnes, B. Jr. (Box 2)
  - Barney, Eliza (Box 2)
  - Barnum, Phineas T. 1810-1891 (Box 2)
  - Barratt, Anna, 1838- (Box 2)
  - Barratt, Norris Stanley (Box 2)
  - Barton, Bernard 1784-1841 (Box 2)
  - Bayaud, Theodore (Box 2)
  - Bayley, Solomon (Box 2)
  - Beach Brothers (Box 2)
  - Beal, Calib H. (Box 2)
  - Beal, George W. (Box 2)
  - Bechot, Edmund (Box 2)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887 (Box 2)
  - Beem, Martin (Box 2)
  - Bellamy, S.B. (Box 2)
  - Bellew, Frank (Box 2)
  - Beman, Samuel (Box 2)
  - Bemit, C. (Box 2)
  - Bemis, George 1816-1878 (Box 2)
  - Benjamin, Park, 1809-1864 (Box 2)
  - Bennett, De Rohigne Mortimer, 1818-1882 (Box 2)
  - Berry, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Betty, Edward (Box 2)
  - Bickham, William Denison, 1827-1894 (Box 2)
  - Bierstadt, Albert, 1830-1902 (Box 2)
  - Bing, Julius (Box 2)
  - Bird, Francis William, 1809-1894 (Box 2)
  - Birdsall, S.H. (Box 2)
  - Birney, James Gillespie, 1792-1837 (Box 2)
  - Blackler, Ward H. (Box 2)
  - Blackwell, Elizabeth (1821-1910) (Box 2)
  - Blair, Montgomery 1813-1883 (Box 2)
  - Blancan, P.C. (Box 2)
  - Bliss, James Jr. (?) (Box 2)
  - Blood, Harry Ames, 1838-1901 (Box 2)
  - Bogert, H. E. (Box 2)
  - Bonne, Thomas I (Box 2)
  - Boone, Charles H. (Box 2)
  - Bowditch, Henry Ingersoll 1808-1892 (Box 3)
  - Bowditch, William I. (Box 3)
  - Boveryem, George (Box 3)
  - Boyesen, Hjalmar Hjorth l848-l895 (Box 3)
  - Bradburn, George (Box 3)
  - Bradley, Ellin Bertha (Box 3)
  - Bradley, John (Box 3)
  - Bramhall, F.C. (Box 3)
  - Brewer, M. (Box 3)
  - Brewer, Mary Grey (Box 3)
  - Brewster, Frederick Carroll (Box 3)
  - Boyle, J.B. (Box 3)
  - Briggs, Charles Frederick (Box 3)
  - Brigham, Charles D. (Box 3)
  - Brisbane, William Henry, ca. 1803-1878 (Box 3)
  - Brockman, S. (Box 3)
  - Brokaw, Estella Bachman (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Samuel (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Issac A (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Noah 1830-1903 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Benjamin (Box 3)
  - Brown, Mrs. Clare Herbert (Box 3)
  - Brown, John 1800-1859: Printed items (Box 3)
  - Brown, John H. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Mary A. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Sarah A./Wallace J.H. (Box 3)
  - Brown, Walter (Box 3)
  - Brown, William W. (Box 3)
  - Browne, John W. (Box 4)
  - Browne, Junius Henri, 1833-1902 (Box 4)
  - Browne, Martha (Griffith) d. 1906 (Box 4)
  - Browne, William Hand, 1828-1912 (Box 4)
  - Bruce, Georgina (Box 4)
  - Bryant, William Cullen 1794-l878 (Box 4)
  - Buckingham. Rev. E. (Box 5)
  - Buekeley, Richard (Box 5)
  - Bungay, George Washington, 1818-1892 (Box 5)
  - Bunker, Chang and Eng, 1811-1874 (Box 5)
  - Burdick, Clara DeWolf (Box 5)
  - Burdick, Mabel L. (Box 5)
  - Burleigh, C.M. (Box 5)
  - Burleigh, Charles Calistus, 1810-1878 (Box 5)
  - Burleigh, Florence A. (Box 5)
  - Burleigh, Margaret J. (Box 5)
  - Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1829-1881 (Box 5)
  - Burlingame, Edward Livermore 1848-1922 (Box 5)
  - Butler, Benjamin Franklin, 1818-1893 (Box 5)
  - Butler, James Davie, 1815-1905 (Box 5)
  - Butler, Mrs. Josephine Elizabeth Grey, 1828-1906 (Box 5)
  - Byington, A. Homer (Box 6)
  - Byron, Ann Isabella (Milbanke) baroness (Box 6)
  - Byron, George (Box 6)
  - Cabin[?], Caroline F. (Box 6)
  - Cabot, Samuel (Box 6)
  - Calhoun, L. S. G (Box 6)
  - Campbell, A. (Box 6)
  - Carey, Henry B.? (Box 6)
  - Caro, Pauline Cassin (Mrs. E.M.) (Box 6)
  - Carpender, E. M. (Box 6)
  - Carpenter, E. W. (Box 6)
  - Carpenter, Henry (Box 6)
  - Carroll, William A. (Box 6)
  - Carrow, Emma M. (Box 6)
  - Carter, Robert, 1819-1879 (Box 6)
  - Cass, Hiram (Box 6)
  - Cavender, Thomas S. (Box 6)
  - Cerydin (?) J.F. (Box 6)
  - Chadwick, J.B. (Box 6)
  - Chadwick, John White, 1840-1904 (Box 6)
  - Channing, William Henry, 1810-1884 (Box 6)
  - Chapin, Elizabeth M. Gay (Mrs. Jacob) (Box 7)
  - Chapin, Laura (Box 7)
  - Chapman, Elizabeth B. (Box 7)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston (Box 7)
  - Chapman, Mary G (Box 8)
  - Chapman, W (Box 8)
  - Chase, Salmon Portland, 1808-1873 (Box 8)
  - Cheever, Henry Theodore, 1814-1897 (Box 8)
  - Child, David Lee, 1794-1874 (Box 8)
  - Child, Lydia Maria, 1802-1880 (Box 8)
  - Chur, A.T. (Box 8)
  - Churchill, McKeen G. (Box 8)
  - Clarke, Robert (Box 8)
  - Churchman, Samuel (Box 8)
  - Claflen, William (Box 8)
  - Clapp, Henry, Jr (Box 8)
  - Clancey, John S. (Box 8)
  - Clark, Anna Charles (Mrs. Hobert) (Box 8)
  - C1arke, George L. (Box 8)
  - Clark, Hobart (Box 8)
  - Clark, S. T. (Box 8)
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888 (Box 8)
  - Clarkson, Mary (Box 8)
  - Clarkson, Thomas, 1760-1846 (Box 8)
  - Clay, Cassius Marcellus, 1810-1903 (Box 8)
  - Clay, Henry, 1777-1852 (Box 8)
  - Claybourn, Louisa (Box 8)
  - Cleveland, John L (?) (Box 8)
  - Close, Maud M (Box 8)
  - Cobden, Richard, 1804-1885 (Box 8)
  - Coohrane, John, 1813-1898 (Box 8)
  - Colburn, Richard T (Box 8)
  - Colfax, Schuyler, 1823-1885 (Box 8)
  - Collins, John Anderson (Box 8)
  - Cornstock, N (Box 8)
  - Comstock, Phoebe Ann (Box 9)
  - Cogdon, Charles T. (Box 9)
  - Congdon, Charlotte (Box 9)
  - Conkling, Roscoe 1829-1888 (Box 9)
  - Conover, S. (Box 9)
  - Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1832-1907 (Box 9)
  - Cook, Clarence, 1828-1900 (Box 9)
  - Cope, Alexis T. (Box 9)
  - Cordier, W.B. (Box 9)
  - Corne, W.F. (Box 9)
  - Costelle, Joseph C. (Box 9)
  - Couzins, Phoebe Wilson, 1842-1913 (Box 9)
  - Craft, David (Box 10)
  - Crandal, W.L. (Box 10)
  - Craffut, William Augustus, 1835-1915 (Box 10)
  - Crounse, Lorenzo, 1834-1898 (Box 10)
  - Crummell, Alexander, 1819-1898 (Box 10)
  - Crummell, Henry Richard (Box 10)
  - Culosky, Francis (Box 10)
  - Culver, E.D., 1803-1889 (Box 10)
  - Cumming, Edward Hamilton (Box 10)
  - Cummins, A.M. (Box 10)
  - Cunningham, William and James (Box 10)
  - Curtis, Anna Shaw, 1836-1923 (Box 10)
  - Curtis, Cornelius (Box 10)
  - Curtis, George William, 1824-1892 (Box 10)
  - Curtis, Julia B. (Box 10)
  - Custer, Elizabeth Bacon, 1842-1939 (Box 10)
  - Dall, Caroline (Healey), 1822-1912 (Box 10)
  - Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895 (Box 10)
  - Darling, Samuel C. (Box 10)
  - Davenport, George D (Box 10)
  - Davenport, John I. (Box 10)
  - Davis, Alex M. (Box 10)
  - Davis, Benjamin B. (Box 10)
  - Davis, Edward M. (Box 11)
  - Davis, Georgina A. (Box 11)
  - Davis, Henry Winter, 1817-1865 (Box 11)
  - Davis, John W.C. (Box 11)
  - Davis, Milton (Box 11)
  - Davis, P.W. See: Wright, Paulina (Box 11)
  - Davison, Emma (Box 11)
  - Davison. Edward F. (Box 11)
  - Dawes, Henry Laurens, 1816-1903 (Box 11)
  - Day, Mary C. (Box 11)
  - Deane, Charles (Box 11)
  - DeBow, S.H. (Box 11)
  - Delta, P.F. (Box 11)
  - Demorest, Mme. Ellen Louise (Box 11)
  - Denison, Charles Wheeler, 1809-1881 (Box 11)
  - Denny, Henry G. (Box 11)
  - Denslow, V.B. (Box 11)
  - Depew, Chauncey Mitchell (Box 11)
  - De Peyster, August (Box 11)
  - Des Cassayrs, Charles (Box 11)
  - Dewar, John (Box 11)
  - Dewees, Watson W. (Box 11)
  - DeWolf, Benjamin (Box 11)
  - Dexter, Wirt, 1832-1890 (Box 11)
  - Dicey, Albert Venn (Box 11)
  - Dillingham, John H. (Box 11)
  - Divine, S.R. (Box 11)
  - Divinelle, John W. (Box 11)
  - Doll, E. Adams (Box 11)
  - Doll and Richards (Box 11)
  - Donaldson, F. (Box 11)
  - Donaldson, Thomas (Box 11)
  - Dorr, M.S.W. (Box 11)
  - Doty, Julia (Box 11)
  - Doubleday, Abner, 1819-1893 (Box 11)
  - Douglass, Frederick, 1817-1895 (Box 11)
  - Draper, John William, 1811-1882 (Box 11)
  - Draper, Lymen Copeland, 1815-1891 (Box 11)
  - Driscoll, Frederick (Box 11)
  - Driscoll, J. (Box 11)
  - Dubney, J. (Box 11)
  - DuBois, Anna S. (Box 11)
  - Du Chaillu, Paul Belloni (Box 11)
  - Du Chadlin (?) P.B. (Box 11)
  - Dunn, Mary A. (Box 11)
  - Durkee, Sarah A. (Box 11)
  - Dustin, Abby Gay (Box 11)
  - Dutton, O.H. (Box 11)
  - Duyckinck, Evert Augustus (Box 11)
  - Dwight, W. (Box 11)
  - Eaton, John (Box 12)
  - Edson, Obed (Box 12)
  - Ela, J.N. (Box 12)
  - Elder, Cyrus, 1883-1912 (Box 12)
  - Elliot, William Waight, 1831-1889 (Box 12)
  - Elliot, William Greenleaf, 1811-1887 (Box 12)
  - Ellis, Edward Sylvester, 1849-1916 (Box 12)
  - Ellis, George Edward, 1814-1894 (Box 12)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 12)
  - Emerson, Sarah Hopper Gibbons (Box 12)
  - England, Isaac W. (Box 12)
  - Enwright, Y. (Box 12)
  - Epson, Elizabeth (Box 12)
  - Ericsson, John, 1803-1889 (Box 12)
  - Erving, John, 1833-1917 (Box 12)
  - Estlin, Mary A. (Box 12)
  - Evans, E. John (Box 12)
  - Evening Post (Box 12)
  - Everett, Edward, 1794-1865 (Box 12)
  - Fairbanks, Josephine N. (Box 12)
  - Farnham, Eliza W. (Box 12)
  - Fay, Theodore Sedgwick, 1807-1989 (Box 12)
  - Feistpo, R.E. (Box 12)
  - Fenton, Ruben Eaton, 1819-1885 (Box 12)
  - Fernald, Charles, 1830-1892 (Box 12)
  - Field, David Dudley, 1805-1894 (Box 12)
  - Fields, Annie (Adams), 1834-1915 (Box 12)
  - Fields, James Thomas, 18l6-l88l (Box 12)
  - Firth Pond and Company (Box 12)
  - Finley, John Huston, 1863-1940 (Box 12)
  - Fiske, Mary Alleyne (Box 12)
  - Fiske, Mary Otis Gay (Mrs. Robert T.P.), 1809-1852 (Box 12)
  - Fiske, Oliver (Box 12)
  - Fiske, Robert Tarat Paine, 1800-1866 (Box 12)
  - Fiske, Sarah Duncan (Box 13)
  - Floyd, Nicoll (Box 13)
  - Flynn, A. Harriet (Box 13)
  - Flynn, J.T. (Box 13)
  - Flower, Frank Abial, 1854-1911 (Box 13)
  - Follen, Charles (Box 13)
  - Follen, Eliza Lee (Cabot) (Mrs. Charles), 1787-1860 (Box 13)
  - Fonda, A.A. (Box 13)
  - Foote, Henry Stuart, l804-l880 (Box 13)
  - Forbes, John Murray 1813-1898 (Box 13)
  - Forbes, W.H. (Box 13)
  - Forman, J. Gilbert (Box 13)
  - Forsyth, James R. (Box 13)
  - Foster, Abigail (Kelley) 1810-1887 (Box 13)
  - Foster, Daniel (Box 14)
  - Foster, Stephen Symonds, 1809-1887 (Box 14)
  - Foulke, Hugh (Box 14)
  - Fowkes, H. (Box 14)
  - Francis, R.D. (Box 14)
  - Franklin, William Buel, 1823-1903 (Box 14)
  - Fremont, Jessie Benton, 1824-1902 (Box 14)
  - Fremont, John Charles, 1813-1890 (Box 14)
  - French, M (Box 14)
  - French, William S. (Box 14)
  - Fry, Edward P. (Box 14)
  - Fry, Horace (Box 14)
  - Fry, J.R. (Box 14)
  - Fry, W.H. (Box 14)
  - Fuller, W.J.A. (Box 14)
  - Futhey, J. Smith (Box 14)
  - Furness, William Henry 1802­1896 (Box 14)
  - Fussell, Edwin (Box 14)
  - Fussell, Bartholomew, 1794-1871 (Box 14)
  - Gage, Frances Dana Barker, 1808-1884 (Box 14)
  - Gardner, Charles Kitchell 1787-l869 (Box 14)
  - Garnaud, C (Box 14)
  - Garrett, E.S. (Box 14)
  - Garrett, Philip (Box 14)
  - Garrett, R.C. (Mrs, Wm) (Box 14)
  - Garrison, Francis Jackson, 1848-1916 (Box 14)
  - Garrison, Wendell Philips, 1840-1907 (Box 14)
  - Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879 (Box 15)
  - Gassett, Edward (Box 15)
  - Gay, Arthur Otis (Box 16)
  - Gay, Charles W. (Box 17)
  - Gay, Ebenezer, 1818-1899 (Box 18)
  - Gay, Eleanor Allen (Mrs, Martin) (Box 18)
  - Gay, Elizabeth Neall, 1840-1859 (Box 19)
  - Gay, Elizabeth Neall, 1860-1871 (Box 19A)
  - Gay, Elizabeth Neall, 1872-1873 (Box 19B)
  - Gay, Elizabeth Neall, 1874-undated (Box 20)
  - Gay, Elizabeth Tarbell (Mrs. Henry) (Box 21)
  - Gay, Ellen (Mrs, Ebenezer) (Box 21)
  - Gay, Francis M (Box 21)
  - Gay, Henry P (Box 21)
  - Gay, Howard (Box 21)
  - Gay, Jotham (Box 21)
  - Gay, Nelly Blood (Box 21)
  - Gay, Martin (Box 21)
  - Gay, Mary Alleyne Otis (Box 22)
  - Gay, Sarah Mifflin, 1861-1897 (Box 23)
  - Gay, Sarah Mifflin, undated (Box 24)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, 1835-1839 (Box 25)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, 1841-October 1844 (Box 26)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, November 1844-May 1845 (Box 27)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, June 1845-June 1846 (Box 28)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, July 1846-1849 (Box 29)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, 1850-1859 (Box 30)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, 1860-November 17, 1883 (Box 31)
  - Gay, Sidney Howard, undated (Box 32)
  - Gay, Walter (Box 33)
  - Gay, Winckworth Allan (Box 33)
  - George, Henry (Box 34)
  - Gibbons, Abby (Hopper), 1801-1893 (Box 34)
  - Gibbons, Julia (Box 34)
  - Gibbons, W.H. (Box 34)
  - Gibbs, Wolcott, 1822-1908 (Box 34)
  - Gibson, William Hamilton, 1850-l896 (Box 34)
  - Giddings, Joshus Reed, 1795-l864 (Box 34)
  - Gilbert, Howard Worcester, 1819-1894 (Box 34)
  - Gilly, Edward (Box 34)
  - Gilmarsh, James R. (Box 34)
  - Gilmore, James R. (Box 34)
  - Gillmore, Quincy Adams, 1825-1888 (Box 34)
  - Gladstone, J.P. (Box 34)
  - Godkin, Edwin Lawrence, 1831-1902 (Box 34)
  - Godwin, Parke (Box 34)
  - Goodell, William, 1792­1878 (Box 34)
  - Goodenow, Daniel (Box 34)
  - Goodrich and Huntington (Box 34)
  - Goreham, Col. Joseph (Box 35)
  - Gould, A.P. (Box 35)
  - Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1787-1859 (Box 35)
  - Gove, Mary S. [Nichols, Mary S.Q., 1810-1884] (Box 35)
  - Gowing, E.H. (Box 35)
  - Graham, Walter (Box 35)
  - Gratacap, Louis P. (Box 35)
  - Great Britain. Postmaster General (Box 35)
  - Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872 (Box 35)
  - Green, Frances H. (Box 35)
  - Green, Frank B. (Box 35)
  - Green, Horace, 1802-1866 (Box 35)
  - Greene, William G (Box 35)
  - Grew, Mary (Box 35)
  - Grey, T.C. (Box 36)
  - Griffith, Mattie (Box 36)
  - Griggs, William C. (Box 36)
  - Grimké, Charlotte Forster (Box 36)
  - Grimké, Sarah Moore, 1792-1873 (Box 36)
  - Griscem, John D (Box 36)
  - Griswold, Rufus Wilmot, 1815-1857 (Box 36)
  - Gunn, Thomas Butler (Box 36)
  - Gurley, W.H. (Box 36)
  - Gurowski, Adam, 1805-1865 (Box 36)
  - H., Charles (Box 36)
  - H,.N.F. (Box 36)
  - Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909 (Box 36)
  - Hale, Sarah Josepha (Box 36)
  - Hall, Edward H. (Box 36)
  - Hall, Jonathan P. (Box 36)
  - Hall, W.A. (Box 36)
  - Hallanell, Richard P. (Box 36)
  - Hallett, Charles (Box 36)
  - Hallock, Edward (Box 36)
  - Hallock, Nicholas (Box 36)
  - Hallock, Sarah H. (Box 36)
  - Halpine, Charles Graham, 1829-1868 (Box 36)
  - Halstead, Murat, 1829-1908 (Box 36)
  - Hambleton, James Pinkney, ca 1830-1890 (Box 36)
  - Hamilton, James Alexander, 1788-1878 (Box 36)
  - Hamlin, Charles Eugene, 1861-1921 (Box 36)
  - Hammond, James B. (Box 36)
  - Hanscom, L.R. (Box 37)
  - Hanscom, Simon Parker (Box 37)
  - Hardenbrook, Ellie L. (Mrs. John A.) (Box 37)
  - Hardenbrook, John A (Box 37)
  - Harned, William (Box 37)
  - Harney, G.S. (Box 37)
  - Harper, Fletcher, 1806-1877 (Box 37)
  - Harper, Samuel (Box 37)
  - Harper & Bros. (Box 37)
  - Harvey, E.L. (Box 37)
  - Harvey, Elizabeth (Box 37)
  - Harvey (?), Thomas S. (Box 37)
  - Haskell, Daniel N (Box 37)
  - Hathaway, J,C. (Box 37)
  - Haughton, James (Box 37)
  - Haven, Samuel Forster, 1806-1881 (Box 37)
  - Hawthorne, Julian, 1846-1934 (Box 37)
  - Hayden, Charles (Box 37)
  - Hayden, Horace Edwin, 1837-1917 (Box 37)
  - Hayden, Lewis (Box 37)
  - Haydock, Hannah W. (Box 37)
  - Haydock, Robert (Box 37)
  - Hayes, John E. (Box 37)
  - Hayward, John L (Box 37)
  - Heap, James (Box 37)
  - Hedrick, Benjamin Sherwood, 1827-1886 (Box 37)
  - Henderson, Thomas J. (Box 37)
  - Henford, F.H. (Box 37)
  - Henning, Thomas (Box 37)
  - Henry, Arthur R. (Box 37)
  - Henry, Frank (Box 37)
  - Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 37)
  - Herbert, J.K. (Box 37)
  - Herndon, William Henry, 1818-1891 (Box 37)
  - Hicks, Alice F. (Box 37)
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911 (Box 37)
  - Higginson, Waldo (Box 37)
  - Hildreth, Richard (Box 37)
  - Hill, Adams Sherman (1833-1910), 1862 June – October 1862 (Box 38)
  - Hill, Adams Sherman (1833-1910), November 1862-May 1863 (Box 39)
  - Hill, Adams Sherman (1833-1910), June-October 1863 (Box 40)
  - Hill, Adams Sherman (1833-1910), November 1863 (Box 41)
  - Hills, E. Augustus (Box 41)
  - Hamilton A (Box 41)
  - Hinckley, H.S. (Box 41)
  - Hinckley, Isaac (Box 41)
  - Hinmann, R.R. (Box 41)
  - Hitt, Robert Roberts, 1834-1906 (Box 41)
  - Hoag, Hulda C. (Box 41)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1984 (Box 41)
  - Honney, W. (Box 41)
  - Hooper, Anne S. (Box 41)
  - Hoover, Frederick & Elizabeth (Box 41)
  - Hopper, Anne M (Box 41)
  - Hopper, Edward, 1847 (Box 41)
  - Hopper, Edward, 1848 (Box 42)
  - Hopper, Roasalie (Box 42)
  - Houghton, Mifflin & Co. (Box 42)
  - Howard, Joseph R (Box 42)
  - Howe, Samuel Gridley 18O1-1876 (Box 42)
  - Howells, Theodora N. (Box 42)
  - Howells, William Dean 1837-1911 (Box 42)
  - Howland, Henry S. (Box 42)
  - Hubbard, C.J. (Box 42)
  - Hudson, Erasmus Darwin, 1805-1880 (Box 42)
  - Hudson, Frederic (Box 42)
  - Hulings, Abby Louise Browne (Box 42)
  - Hunt, Charles W., Jr. (Box 42)
  - Hunt, Elizabeth (Box 42)
  - Huntington, W.H. (Box 42)
  - Hurd and Houghton (Box 42)
  - Hurlbut, William Henry l827-1895 (Box 42)
  - Hussey, C.C. (Box 42)
  - Hutchinson, Abby (Box 42)
  - Hutter (?) Robert (Box 42)
  - Ide, A.M. (Box 43)
  - Jackson, Francis (Box 43)
  - Jackson, Francis (Box 43)
  - Jackson, Robert (Box 43)
  - Jacobs, Harriet Brent (Box 43)
  - Jacobs, John S. (Box 43)
  - Jacoby, Henry (Box 43)
  - James, Thomas L. (Box 43)
  - Janney, Samuel McPherson, 1801-1880 (Box 43)
  - Jay, Charles (Box 43)
  - Jay, John, 1817-1894 (Box 43)
  - Jay, William, 1789-1858 (Box 43)
  - Jennings, Helen (Mrs. Allan H.) (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Bessie W (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Dania W. (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Laura W (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Lewis (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Mary W. (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Oliver, 1809-1889 (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Robert J. (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Rossiter, 1840-1931 (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Rowland (Box 43)
  - Johnson, S. (Box 43)
  - Johnson, Tom L. (Box 43)
  - Johnston, Henry Phelps, 1842-1923 (Box 43)
  - Jones, I. Elizabeth (Box 43)
  - Jones, Morven M. (Box 43)
  - Jones, S.C. (Box 43)
  - Judd, Rev. Sylverster (Box 43)
  - Judson, S.H. (Box 43)
  - Justice, Anna Neall (Mrs. Theodore) (Box 43)
  - Justice, Eliza Neall (Mrs. William) (Box 43)
  - Justice, Elvira N. (Box 43)
  - Justice, Hilda (Box 43)
  - Justice, William W. (Box 43)
  - Kane, Thomas S. (Box 44)
  - Kasaka, A. (Box 44)
  - Kellogg, Mrs John Harvey (Box 44)
  - Kemp, Susan B (Box 44)
  - Kent, William H (Box 44)
  - Kidwell, Cleo H (Box 44)
  - Kidwell, Mr & Mrs (Box 44)
  - Kimber, Abbie, 1845 (Box 44)
  - Kimber, Abbie, 1846- (Box 45)
  - King, Gladys (Box 45)
  - King, Samuel (Box 45)
  - Kinman, Mrs. (Box 45)
  - Kinman, Seth (Box 45)
  - Kipel, G. (Box 45)
  - Kirby, Georgiana Bruce (Mrs. Richard) (Box 45)
  - Kite, William (Box 45)
  - Knox, Thomas Wallace, 1835-1896 (Box 45)
    This file is missing and is currently unavailable for use.
  - Kollock, Mrs. S.H. (Box 45)
  - Kossuth, Lajos, 1802-1894 (Box 45)
  - Landon, Melville De Lancey, 1839-1910 (Box 45)
  - Langarl, John A (Box 45)
  - Langhorne, Louisa (Box 45)
  - Lathrop, George Parsons, 1851-1898 (Box 45)
  - Latimer, Charles l827-l888 (Box 45)
  - Latto, Thomas C (Box 45)
  - Leach, Phineas. (Box 45)
  - Leach, J. Granville (Box 45)
  - Leland, Warren (Box 45)
  - Lemmer, Rachel Sumner (Box 45)
  - Lenihan, Ernest (Box 45)
  - Lermonsoil, A.H. (Box 45)
  - Lesley, Peter, 1819-1903 (Box 45)
  - Lesley, Susan Inches (Lyman) (Box 45)
  - Leverence, Henry L. (Box 45)
  - Levinston, J.S. (Box 45)
  - Lewis, Charlotte S (Box 45)
  - Lewis, E.M. (Box 45)
  - Lewis, Sarah (Box 45)
  - Liberman, I. (Box 45)
  - Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872 (Box 45)
  - Lieber, Matilda Oppenheimer (Box 45)
  - Lincoln, Arthur (Box 45)
  - Lincoln, Elisa (Box 45)
  - Lincoln, Jarius (Box 45)
  - Lincoln, Solomon (Box 45)